Joy Chen

Cary, NC 27513 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joy-chen-5069/ Cell: (919) 448-4416

GitHub: https://github.com/joychen5069

Email: joychen5069@gmail.com Portfolio: https://joy-chen-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

A highly-motivated Full-Stack Developer with extensive git knowledge with pull requests and code reviews. With experience in React, JavaScript, ¡Query, CSS, HTML, Git, and other front-end frameworks as well as backend RESTful API calls. Database experience with MySQL and MongoDB with Heroku deployment. Experience in an Agile environment with extensive customer support skills along with public relations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Node.Js, ReactJS, React, Express, JavaScript, ¡Query, git, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Mongoose, Handlebars, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, APIs, Heroku, JSON, ES6+
- OSSI CAD, RMS, Criminal Justice, Emergency Services

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

COVID-19 Application | Full Stack Developer

Github: https://github.com/joychen5069/COVID-App **Deployed Site:** https://covid-resource-app.herokuapp.com/

COVID-19 allows you to track how your county is doing with current active cases and deaths as well as provide a COVID symptom checker to provide medical advice.

- Role: Utilized APIs from New York Times for news, Infermedica for symptom checking, and News.Azure for current COVID data. A dynamic front-end using React.JS and Bootstrap. Full MVC pattern to communicate with a Mongoose database to store user information. Passport user authentication for personalized user experience.
- Utilized: React.JS, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, JS/jQuery, Heroku, Bootstrap, and **CSS**

Book Club Application | Full Stack Developer

Github: https://github.com/joychen5069/BookClub

Deployed Site: https://book-club-application.herokuapp.com/

Book Club application helps you keep track of what your book club is reading and allows you to join other book clubs based on interests

- Role: Leveraged APIs from New York Times and Google Books for a source of data using jQuery AJAX. Created a front-end view using Handlebars styled with Materialize and CSS. Used a full MVC pattern to communicate with a MySQL database to store and change data. Express server set up to request the use of built in Express-Routes from Node modules
- Utilized: MySQL, NodeJs, Express, Handlebars, JS/jQuery, Heroku, Materialize, and CSS

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Web Development Certificate - University of North Carolina , Raleigh, NC | 2020

 A 24-week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Mongoose, Handlebars, JSX, git, Github, APIs, Heroku, Es6+

Bachelor's of Arts in Peace, War, and Defense - National and International Security University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill | May 2017

Minor in Historical Studies

WORK EXPERIENCE

HotelMap, London, UK - Customer Assistant Team | February 2020 - April 2020 Customer Service Team member who meet and exceeded daily and weekly goals set by the training team to ensure customer satisfaction

- Communicated empathy and reassured customers during the emergence of COVID-19 and assisted in timely cancellations in regards to company and hotel policies
- Filtered and responded to incoming emails and phone calls for reservations, cancellations, and refunds with constant regard for customers' privacy and needs

Durham Police Department, Durham, NC - Patrol Officer | July 2017 - February 2020 Uniformed patrol officer responsible for a section on the northside of Durham who constantly fulfilled the city's need for police response in a safe and timely manner

- Responded to high-risk and high-stress situations with regard to the public's safety and need to the criminal happenings throughout the city as well as deterred criminal activity through visibility
- Effectively completed reports based on daily activities and calls for service on the events witnessed in addition to assisting the public in non-criminal matters (e.g. welfare checks, redirecting traffic, escorts)
- Engaged in community outreach programs such as, PALs (Police Athletic Leagues), and National Night Out.